Nick Ford

Front End Dev / Jnr Software Dev

nick-ford.com github.com/nford88 089 421 5048 contact@nick-ford.com

About

Over 2 years experience in web development, most of which has been self taught before I commenced my BSc. I am a motivated individual and have a keen interest in front-end development and UX Design. I have great written and oral communication skills with a excellent attention to detail. A patient listener and eager to learn from others, I keep up to date with the latest technologies and frameworks.

Skills

 $\textbf{Strong}\,/\,\text{HTML}, \text{CSS}, \text{jQuery}, \text{Git}, \text{MySQL}, \text{PHP}, \text{Linux}, \text{Responsive Design}.$

Knowledgeable / ES6, Angular.js, MongoDB, Python.

Experience

AG Associates Accountants / Freelance Web Dev

FEB - MAR 2017, CORK, IE

Built an internal application for timelogging and invoicing system Full stack development using Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP

Nova Networks / Freelance Web Dev

JAN 2017, CORK, IE

Revamped existing internal network analytics dashboard Built using Bootstrap.js and Charts.js

Education

BSc (Ord) Digital Technology and Design (Predicted Distinction)

DUBLIN INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, IRELAND / SEPT 2016 - SEPT 2017

Modules included Web and Device Programming, Mobile Web Applications & Server Side Web Development,

BArt (Hons) Sociology and Social Policy (2.1) /

UNIVERSITY OF LEEDS, UK / SEPT 2011 - JUL 2011

Side Projects

David Chu's China Bistro / HTML-jQuery-CSS

Designed and built a responsive website for a Chinese restaurant.

JobScraper / Python-MySQL-HTML-JS

Personalised dashboard of parsed job listings and application tracking.

Work History

Camera TV and Film Technician / Freelance

NATIONWIDE/EUROPEAN / MAR 2012 - DEC 2016

Worked as a technician on many TV Shows and feature films in this fast paced and ever-changing industry with employers including BBC, ITV, AMC Showtime and RTE.

LLoydsTSB Bank Plc / Customer Service Branch Rep

MANCHESTER, UK / JAN 2005 - APR 2008

Cashier and customer service representative for a large high street bank.